Contact

lindsay.nicole.fleming@gmai l.com

www.linkedin.com/in/lindsay-n-fleming-bsn-rn-ccrn-30aa58102 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare

Hospitals

Nursing

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Trauma Nursing Core Course - TNCC®

Board of Registration in Nursing

Advanced Cardiovascular Life Support (ACLS)

Basic Life Support (BLS)

Progressive Care Nursing Certification - PCCN®

Lindsay N. Fleming BSN, RN, CCRN

Critical Care Nurse and Aesthetic Injector

Wakefield, Massachusetts

Summary

Experienced Bachelors prepared registered nurse with clinical nursing excellence and servant leadership in several academic teaching hospitals in the Boston area.

Magna Cum Laude graduate of Saint Anselm College, Class of 2014.

Sigma Theta Tau International Honors Society of Nursing member, Epsilon Tau-At-Large Chapter.

Additional clinical interests include patient advocacy, spirituality and mindfulness in healing and recovery, pathopharmacology, holistic nutrition, cardiology, and anesthesia.

Experience

Brigham and Women's Hospital Critical Care Float Pool Registered Nurse October 2019 - Present (10 months)

Boston, Massachusetts

Privatus

Per Diem Private Registered Nurse March 2019 - Present (1 year 5 months)

Lexington, Massachusetts

Deliver private, comprehensive, and autonomous nursing care with a unique focus on the patient experience; support lifestyle and personal preferences for those facing temporary or long-term health or age-related issues; develop and foster ongoing relationships with clients during times of transition; conduct health maintenance visits, medication administration including IV infusions, and hospice care; serve clients in areas including but not limited to the Greater Boston area, Cape Cod and The Islands, Manhattan, and Connecticut; assist

clients with medical needs while on business or leisure travel both domestically and internationally.

Owner, Bespoke Beauty
Boutique and Concierge Aesthetic Nurse Injector
2018 - Present (2 years)

Deliver in-depth, one-on-one aesthetic consultation in the comfort of the home, hotel room, office, or spa suite; perform minor cosmetic procedures including neurotoxins and dermal filler injectables, chemical peels, and dermaplaning with an elegant touch and fine attention to detail; using immaculate technique, sterile instruments, and maximal discretion, patients have bespoke cosmetic needs met without disrupting their busy schedule.

*All care overseen by medical director. Certified through the Aesthetic Institute of Massachusetts. Completed expert training on advanced injectable procedures and techniques at Dr. Lara Devgan's Beauty Metrics Master Class in New York, New York.

Laser Gentle Medical Spa Aesthetic Nurse Injector March 2019 - October 2019 (8 months) Burlington, Massachusetts

MelroseWakefield Healthcare Critical Care Registered Nurse October 2018 - September 2019 (1 year) Melrose. Massachusetts

Provide expert, evidence-based nursing in a 14-bed acute critical care area focused on treating patients with unstable complex medical pathology, cardiac disorders, hemodynamic derangements, respiratory failure, hepato-renal disease, and various surgical issues; specialize in ventilatory support, high-alert medication titration, CVVH, and resuscitative measures; independently synthesize patient data to guide clinical decision making and treatment goals; collaborate with Tufts Medical Center attending physicians, fellows, and midlevel practitioners to ensure positive patient outcomes and high-quality, community-centered care.

Addison Gilbert Hospital
Emergency Department Registered Nurse
March 2018 - October 2018 (8 months)

Gloucester, Massachusetts

Facilitated ongoing treatment of patients of all ages presenting with various types of trauma and illness at both Addison Gilbert Hospital and Beverly Hospital; independently assessed and treated life-threatening conditions utilizing the ESI triage model; offered psychosocial counseling and support to patients in crisis; managed ventilated patients; inserted peripheral IV's, and accessed Port-A-Cath devices; actively assisted with procedures including conscious sedation, central line insertion, cardioversion, hypothermia treatment after cardiac arrest, and intubation; fulfilled the goals and needs of peers and fellow staff members through servant leadership while maintaining the purpose and mission of the Lahey Health organization.

Boston Medical Center (BMC) Critical Care Registered Nurse May 2017 - July 2017 (3 months)

Boston, Massachusetts

Completed eight weeks of clinical orientation while attending the Boston ICU Consortium didactic program, which serves to create a foundation of knowledge for nurses entering critical care; delivered community-based critical care nursing to diverse patient groups at the largest safety-net hospital and busiest provider of trauma and emergency services in New England; left position to personally undergo major surgery and rehabilitation.

Beth Israel Lahey Health Float Pool Registered Nurse October 2014 - April 2017 (2 years 7 months)

Float Pool/Nursing Resource Team

Met needs of various patient populations faced with multifaceted health conditions on all medical-surgical units, telemetry floors, and the emergency department; served as an advocate and liaison while providing individualized, holistic, and culturally congruent care; achieved patient goals through collaboration with health care team members while developing and maintaining professional relationships and seeking out new learning opportunities; taught, counseled, supported, and facilitated the coordination of inpatient care in an effort to restore optimal health and wellness; awarded "Champion of Care" recognition from former Lahey CEO Dr. Joanne Conroy for clinical nursing excellence and extraordinary compassionate care at the bedside.

Beverly Hospital
Perianesthesia Clinical Associate
April 2012 - October 2014 (2 years 7 months)
Post Anesthesia Care Unit (PACU)

,

Assisted with the delivery and flow of patient care under the direction of the registered nurse and anesthesia staff; safely and accurately performed diagnostic, therapeutic, and administrative procedures and tasks; demonstrated ability and willingness to participate in the patient care team as a multi-skilled caregiver; remained flexible in response to changing needs and priorities of the holding area, PACU, surgical day care, and pre-admission testing offices.

Beth Israel Lahey Health
Senior Preceptorship and Capstone
January 2014 - May 2014 (5 months)
Medical Intensive Care Unit (MICU)

Attained 200 clinical hours of one-to-one experience with a senior BSN-prepared nurse, providing state-of-the-art, evidenced-based nursing care; applied independent clinical decision-making to support collaborative care plans and clinical conclusions; enthusiastically accepted challenging patient assignments and nursing tasks; provided comprehensive and detailed patient reports at change of shift; eagerly sought out additional learning opportunities and became integrated and welcomed into the MICU team.

Saint Anselm College Student Nurse January 2010 - May 2014 (4 years 5 months) Clinical Rotations

Collaborated with peers, nursing professors, clinical faculty and hospital staff in delivering holistic nursing care in a variety of settings including but not limited to Catholic Medical Center, Concord Hospital, Southern New Hampshire Medical Center and Crotched Mountain Hospital; offered self-motivated leadership and support to fellow students while providing hope and encouragement to patients and their families.

Education

Saint Anselm College
Bachelor of Science in Nursing · (2009 - 2014)

Waterville Valley Academy (2005 - 2009)